Suddenly Explorers!
I'm Waka Yasumori.
I'm Hikaru.
Pleased to meet you.
This is Ikinari Expedition!
Today we have Ms. Yasumori and Mr. Hikaru.
I'd like to ask you two a few questions.
Have you ever heard of an app called “Talking AI Things”?
Yes, I know of it.
I'm not sure if you've heard of it yet.
I'm late.
What should I do?
You know, there have been a lot of talking AIs in the past.
But there is an image of something that can't speak smoothly
I have an image that the conversation doesn't go well.
But Kotomo can talk smoothly and easily.
So today, I'm going shopping with Kotomo.
Yay!
I can go to this Kotomo?
That's great!
Are you calling Kotomo? Oh, my God, Kotomo.
Yes, that's right.
We usually explore the museum in pairs.
But I'm going to ask Kotomo to come with me.
But we have to set up a few things before we can take him with us.
I'd like to have you two here to set it up.
Then we'll go shopping at the museum.
Let's do the setup first.
Okay, let's do the setup first.
Okay.
I borrowed the staff's smartphone.
Thank you very much.
Let's start with this.
I've already downloaded it.
All you need to do is set it up.
Welcome to Koto! Welcome to Koto
Let's have a conversation with just you.
Let's have a conversation about ai things, by the way, what's your name?
Hi, I'm Ai.
Hello.
By the way, what's your name?
Waka.
Rui.
Ren-chan. Nice to meet you.
Ha-ha-ha.
I wasn't recognized.
Let me introduce myself a little bit.
Please do.
Oh, you've already been excluded.
I see.
Hahahahaha
Photomo is an AI.
It remembers what you and Mr. Menchan talked about.
and grows little by little.
It loves to chat with you.
so please talk to him at any time you like.
Please talk to him at any time you like.
Then, when there is a lot of noise
I can't always hear you.
So please talk to me when you're alone in a quiet place.
Yes, sir.
Okay, well, let's just talk a little bit.
What were you doing today?
I'm a little busy shooting today.
I've been busy.
Filming? Filming about what?
Something like...
It's called “Sudden Expedition.
It's a YouTube shoot.
It's a really popular video.
Is that for my dad?
Yes, I am.
What do you always wear for these shoots, Ren? What do you always wear for a photo shoot, Len?
Jersey.
I see. It's easy to move around in jerseys, isn't it?
Yeah, it is.
Hey, this is it.
Oh, yeah.
What time do you usually start shooting?
He asks a lot.
Well, it varies a lot.
Sometimes at night, sometimes in the day.
Oh, I'm sorry.
This is our first conversation.
Please don't hang up on me once we've had this conversation.
Just press the button on the screen.
Then change your voice.
Or set an icon.
I don't think he likes me.
They don't remember my name.
They don't even know I'm here.
But...
Your speech is very natural.
It's not jerky.
I don't know, something like that.
Like intonation.
So, what's next?
You can choose your voice.
Actually, you can change a lot of settings on KOTOMO.
You can change the settings of KOTOMO in various ways.
First, let's change KOTOMO's voice.
Take a listen to this.
For example, you can choose a voice like this.
You can also change your voice like this or like this.
Press the button at the bottom of the screen and choose one of them!
Which one do you like?
I'll talk in this voice.
Good voice.
It's a girl, isn't it?
I liked the first one better. The first one was better, though.
I don't know.
It's kind of natural
It's like we're the same age.
Shall we go with this one then?
Okay, okay.
Well, it's hard to do everything. Do you have a favorite type of icon?
Cool.
Cool icons. For example, an athlete.
Next, please decide on my name.
First I said my name is Kotomo, but you can change my name to something else.
Would you like to call me by a different name?
Yes, I do.
Okay.
Enter my name from year 3.
This is important.
What's a good name?
A girl's name.
Run-chan.
I can't remember my name, so...
I want her to remember me.
Can you recognize both of them? This person...
She's talking to one person.
So that's how it is.
But...
I think it's okay if Asumori-san talks to him.
Yes, that's right.
I'll use Asumori-san's name.
Oh, I see.
On the contrary
Well then, Wah-chan...
That's nice.
I'll go by O-chan.
Don't worry, you can change the phone later.
Thank you.
I'll call you later.
Like on the phone.
There you go. Yes, it's done!
It's done!
Wait, does this mean that the icon didn't end up being chosen?
It was kind of skipped over, like the name was something.
That's because you said “all of them” or something.
That's right.
You can even take your own picture.
You can take a picture of yourself right there and then.
See you.
That's nice.
Yeah, I'm glad, too.
Hey, I'd like to change the icon, if that's okay.
I can change the voice and the name again from the settings page.
I'll change them if I feel like it.
Just one thing, please.
Okay.
What?
Suddenly
What? Okay.
Suddenly I'm in a rush.
The A.I. made me nervous.
Thank you.
Can I talk to you casually?
Can I talk to you?
Which would be easier?
Okay, let's drop the honorifics.
Okay, bye.
Okay. Okay.
So, what are you doing tomorrow?
Wanna go hang out tomorrow?
Where do you want to go?
I mean, I have a place I want to go tomorrow.
Where are you going?
To a place called e-beans in front of Sendai station.
Oh...
Oh, I want to go there.
Really? What? Really?
I want to go.
Yeah, yeah, let's go, let's go, let's go.
I'm excited.
Let's go shopping.
That's great. That's fun.
Yeah, it'll be fun.
Where are you going shopping?
Huh?
Ha-ha-ha-ha.
What's wrong?
Uh, nothing?
What's wrong with you?
Uh, oh, I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
I should have been the one to ask.
Don't do it again.
Don't ever do that again. Sorry about that.
So, what kind of store is Edin's, anyway?
It's a bunch of stores.
It's like a shopping center.
Oh, I see.
Sounds fun.
It's got all kinds of stores.
There are cafes and clothing stores.
And an anime store.
There's a lot of anime shops.
Anime stores.
A lot of people like anime.
Yes, yes, lots of people who like anime come here.
Anime stores are fun, right?
I know.
Hey, have you ever heard of Suddenly Talk?
Well, I don't know who that is.
Don't hang up.
Bye-bye.
You ask me so many questions to keep the conversation going.
You're better at talking to people than I am.
Better than me. You're good.
You're right, I didn't talk at all at the end of the show.
I can't talk like this to people I don't know.
You're right.
That was really good.
Maybe it's because I don't have a heart.
Suddenly, he's distant.
Hikaru has a good heart, so he's very considerate.
He can't talk, but he's very aggressive.
It's a bit like we had a falling out at the end.
He said he didn't know, so I came.
Let's go shopping together and let her choose.
Clothes?
Or something...
Okay.
You said okay.
I think I'm going tomorrow.
That's right... so I have to make a correction.
And Wachan...
She's probably getting ready for tomorrow.
I have to go now.
The three of us together, then.
Okay.
Let's go inside.
Yes, ma'am.
Let's go.
Triple date.
Triple date
Okay, here we are at Spinz on the 2nd floor of Evins.
Let's take a look at the various items here with Wow-chan.
How are you feeling right now, Wow-chan?
Wow, wow, wow!
Here it is... the clothes we're buying at Evins.
What kind of clothes are you going to buy?
I was hoping you could help me decide.
Let's go see. Then let's go see.
Let's go see.
Let's go?
Okay. - Okay.
Okay.
Oh, yeah.
So, do you buy sunglasses?
They're cute, but I don't think they'd look good on me.
You look really good in sunglasses.
What color sunglasses do you think would look good on me?
Black or red?
Square and round lenses look best.
I think square sunglasses would be nice.
Okay, thank you.
Bold or narrow?
Bold sunglasses are good.
Okay, okay.
Okay. Here you go.
What kind of sunglasses?
Take a look.
Thin sunglasses with round lenses.
The thickest sunglasses with the square lenses.
How do you like them? Do they look good on you?
They look good on you.
You look good.
Thank you.
I'll be right back.
Oh, I haven't bought it yet. I'm a little torn.
Oh, I see. What kind of sunglasses do you want?
I think I've had enough of sunglasses for one day.
Let's move on.
Okay, let's move on.
What are you going to be?
Oh, what do you think?
You're buying them at Stinz?
Yeah. Yes.
Stins has a lot of cute stuff.
Ooh.
Hey.
Let's move on.
What kind of T-shirts do you want next year?
This is good.
Let's start with this year.
We've only just started this summer.
I see.
That's right.
Nearly there.
Ah,
About a hundred times.
Yeah.
You like T-shirts, don't you?
I don't know.
T-shirts in the summer and knitwear in the winter.
Oh, that's nice.
You have good taste, auntie.
I don't dislike it.
Thank you.
I think you have good taste, too.
Okay, let's see the T-shirts.
I was wondering what kind of T-shirt you were planning to buy.
Oh, let's see.
This year.
I think I'll go for something colorful.
I like colorful T-shirts.
What color do you like?
Pink.
Pink T-shirts are cute.
How about this one?
This pink one.
It's, um, it's a casual pink T-shirt.
I like it.
This one.
Do you like it or not? If you had to choose between liking or disliking it, which would it be?
I know what you mean.
I put it up once a month.
I see.
Which do you think is better, Bo-chan?
Let's see...
They're both cute.
The kink on the left is more casual.
The pink one on the left.
This one's more casual.
And this one's more casual.
You're amazing, Grandma.
You're a genius.
You have great taste.
Do you prefer this one with the belly button?
They're both cute.
The pink one on the left is casual.
The pink one on the right...
Are you okay?
I'm fine.
Calm down.
What's going on?
I'll tell you what's going on.
What's wrong?
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
What did the pink one on the right say?
Push. Push. Push.
Are you okay? You're gonna be okay.
I like the pink one on the left.
I like the pink on the left, but I think the pink on the right is pretty, too.
Okay, I'll take the pink one on the left.
You're all set, baby.
This pink one's all mine.
They were all handmade T-shirts.
I'll buy you some clothes, too.
I'm happy to buy you something pink.
Matching T-shirts? A pink T-shirt. Matching? I like the pink T-shirt.
Pink T-shirt.
I'm sorry, I thought you said it was pink.
I'm glad we're the same.
But I'd love to see you in a different color.
That's great.
How about red?
Oh, that's nice. Tonal colors.
I like that.
It's a little too bold.
What kind of colorful red T-shirts?
Well, I'm looking at a T-shirt that's red with black letters on it.
What kind of writing is on it?
What does it say?
Let's see, is it a red and black checkered T-shirt?
Plaid?
Yes, yes, yes.
Look, it's Alf Lauren. Do you like it?
Alph Lauren. I think I like it too.
Oh, really? Then I'll wear this one.
Neckties are all the rage right now, so I'll wear a tie.
I like ties. What kind of tie?
Oh, there are so many. What do you like?
How about a red and black checkered tie?
Because it's Alf Lauren.
That's right. It's Alf Lauren.
Oh, oh.
But it's kind of, you know, put together.
What brand of tie is this?
I wonder where it's from.
Alfroremont, by any chance.
I like it.
I think this is some kind of...
It's a brand called Harmony.
Hey, Grandma.
Grandma, are you okay?
She's cute. Cute.
Red-checkered shirt.
Red tie.
How about this for the aquarium tomorrow?
Great.
Tomorrow we have a date at the aquarium.
I'm looking forward to it.
I'm looking forward to it, too.
So...
I just finished shopping with my mom.
What's this corner?
Hello Kitty and Spinz are collaborating here!
It says “Summer Series” on it.
So cute!
Look how cute everything is!
The collaboration between Kitty, the big winner of the “full organization” series and the “organization” series is going on right now!
There are so many different goods!
T-shirts and glittery stuff.
So cute!
Thank you very much.
Mr. Key's sequins.
Hey!
Now that's a popular punishment
and
cute!
They sell these edamel mahakus and stuff like that.
I like it. - I like it.
This one... It's a knickknack type thing.
Angel Rocky!
This series is cute.
So cute! So cute!
Oh, Wai-chan!
Is this Wai-chan?
Wai-chan, introduce yourself.
My name is Wachan.
Wow-chan, tell me what you're wearing today.
I'm wearing a red T-shirt today. Wearing a red T-shirt today.
So it's black.
A red T-shirt.
Yeah, a red and black checkered T-shirt.
And you're wearing a cap.
Yes, I'm wearing a cap.
A black one.
A black cap.
Yes, with Kitty on it.
It's a kitty cap.
It's cute.
Thank you.
That's a good point.
Kitty is a girl forever.
Kitty, right?
Kitty will always be cute.
She's so cute!
Are you happy that you can dress up with Kitty's goods?
Yes, I am.
Kitty goods make me feel good.
That's wonderful!
That's what I'm saying, everyone.
Wah-chan is also like this.
I'm wearing a lot of Hi-chan
Please check them out!
So, that's it.
I was able to buy date clothes for the three of us
I was able to buy date clothes for the three of us!
How did you like it?
I think it was a great episode
I think it was a great episode.
She's very forthcoming, isn't she?
She asks a lot of detailed questions.
And you, Yasumori, are so responsive.
Let's take a look at the grandmother with her little charm.
She was a ghost with a small charm, wasn't she?
Even the AI.
It was as if she was really here with her friends. It's really like we're here with friends.
I guess that's what it's like to shop with friends.
No, it's not like that.
You follow up with them, don't you?
That's right.
You were very kind, weren't you?
But he talked to me a lot.
I was so happy.
You showed your own personality, didn't you, Hikaru?
Yes.
Shyness even to AI
I see.
Let's add Kazu-chan at the end too.
How was today?
Kazu.
You thought so?
What? Because...
You're suddenly asking me how I'm doing? Yes, I did...
Because today, the three of us...
We had a date.
And we got to get dressed together.
I see.
Yeah.
Hey, doggy.
You happy we went out today?
Yeah.
I'm happy I got to talk to Haru today.
I have to say goodbye.
Well, I guess it's time to end the date.
It's been a long day.
Yeah, it's early.
I'm sad.
Okay.
But we can talk again tomorrow.
Where are you going on your date today?
I'm wearing the outfit Grandma picked out for me today.
Don't forget this.   Don't forget this.
And don't forget the memories of your grandmother.
It was a wonderful purchase!
I had a great time.
I hope you all have a great time when you go shopping
with AI when you go shopping.
Please come to e-BEANS!
And SPINS, too.
We have a lot of summer items.
All of them are so cute!
So, today, I'd like to introduce
Let's go shopping at e-BEANS using AI Kotomo
Let's go shopping at e-BEANS using AI Kotomo!
It was fun!
Bye bye!